{"tossups": [{"question": "Prior to coining this three-word phrase, the organization that developed it controversially referred to one of its subjects as a \u201cnincompoop.\u201d An iconic image displaying this phrase shows a man traveling by train from Independence, Missouri to Washington DC. A forecast by Arthur Sears Henning inspired this phrase, a prediction made after polls indicated a Democratic defeat in the 1948 election. For ten points, name this false headline published by the<em> Chicago Daily Tribune</em>.", "answer": "<b> Dewey Defeats Truman</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A ruler of this city has a dream in which he sees a statue with a gold head, a bronze belly, and clay feet. A Biblical figure partially named for this city is described as sitting on top of a scarlet beast with seven heads and ten horns. The Book of Ezekiel was composed while Ezekiel was in this city, which names a whore encountered in the Book of Revelation. The Book of Daniel tells of Nebuchadnezzar II, the ruler of, for ten points, what city where the Jews were held in a namesake period of captivity?", "answer": "<b> Babylon</b> (accept Whore of<b> Babylon</b>; accept<b> Babylon</b>ian Captivity)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "This composer likely hired horn players from Bohemia for the premiere of a piece whose first suite, in F major, includes an \u201cAdagio e staccato\u201d movement. This composer included \u201cLa Paix\u201d [la pay] in a suite for wind band written to celebrate the Treaty of Aix-La-Chapelle, and he included hornpipes in a piece written for a concert for King George I held on a barge on the Thames. For ten points, name this German-born English composer of<em> Music for the Royal Fireworks</em> and<em> Water Music</em>.", "answer": "George Friedrich<b> Handel</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "A politician with this surname campaigned with a Frankenstein doll that declared \u201cYou have nothing to fear with\u201d that man. A woman with this surname won the Senate seat made available by the retirement of Jesse Helms; that woman with this married surname served as Secretary of Transportation under Ronald Reagan and Secretary of Labor under George W. Bush. For ten points, give this surname shared by North Carolina senator Elizabeth and a Kansas senator who lost the 1996 presidential election to Bill Clinton, Bob.", "answer": "<b> Dole</b> (accept Elizabeth<b> Dole</b>; accept Bob<b> Dole</b>) Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "One leader in these conflicts saw a vision of three suns before his victory at Mortimer\u2019s Cross. For switching sides in these conflicts, Richard Neville, the Earl of Warwick, was known as the Kingmaker. These conflicts ended when Richard III was defeated by Henry VII at Bosworth, ushering in the Tudor dynasty. For ten points, name these conflicts between the rival English houses of Lancaster and York, named for their respective red and white flower badges.", "answer": "Wars of the<b> Rose</b>s Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Many perpetrators of this event were tried in Gacaca courts due to a backlog in the traditional justice system. The large number of refugees fleeing this event led to the Great Lakes Crisis in a neighboring country. This event was hastened by rebel forces taking Gisenyi two weeks after the Interahamwe militia lost the capital city of Kigali. Paul Kagame [kuh-GAH-may] became Vice President after the end of, for ten points, what 1994 event in which the Hutus massacred their Tutsi countrymen in a central African country?", "answer": "<b> Rwanda</b>n<b> Genocide</b> (accept descriptions of the<b> genocide of the Tutsis</b>/<b>by the Hutus </b>until \u201cHutu\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This location is home to the Timbisha Shoshone tribe, who use this location\u2019s clay to make a red ochre [\u201coak-er\u201d] paint. Accumulated salts in this location\u2019s Badwater Basin have made its water undrinkable. In July 1913, this location\u2019s Furnace Creek reached 134 degrees Fahrenheit, the hottest temperature ever recorded in the Western hemisphere. For ten points, name this location in the Mojave Desert of California, the lowest point in the US.", "answer": "<b> Death Valley</b> National Park (prompt on Mojave Desert before mentioned; prompt on California before mentioned)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "This battle was preceded by a gift of sports balls to remind the winning king that he should stick to tennis. The fall of Harfleur prompted the losing side to fight this battle. At this battle, the order to kill all prisoners was given after Henry V feared that his baggage train would be overrun. This battle\u2019s losing side could not use cavalry thanks to stakes placed in muddy ground; instead the winning side\u2019s longbowmen fired at will. For ten points, name this 1415 battle fought on St. Crispin\u2019s Day, a victory for England in the Hundred Years\u2019 War.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Agincourt</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In an unfinished story from this collection, Canace finds a falcon who was abandoned by her lover and then shows a romantic interest in her brother, who is also Genghis Khan\u2019s son. In this collection\u2019s first story, Palamon and Arcite fight in a massive battle to win Emily\u2019s hand in marraige. Characters in this work include the Squire and his father, the Knight, who tell stories during their pilgrimage to the shrine of Thomas Becket. For ten points, name this story collection by Geoffrey Chaucer.", "answer": "The<b> Canterbury Tales</b>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Short Fiction"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A type of this disease that makes surgery difficult was discovered by Henry Pancoast. Fritz Lickint experimented with X-raying the spleen as a cure for this disease and coined the term for a \u201cpassive\u201d cause of it. Scientists in Nazi Germany discovered the link between this disease and asbestos. In the late 1990s, Philip Morris admitted that its products cause this disease. For ten points, name this type of cancer often caused by smoking tobacco.", "answer": "<b> lung cancer</b>", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In this election year, the \u201cDraft Muskie\u201d movement emerged to break a deadlocked convention. John B. Anderson ran as an independent in this election. Controversy from the</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Chappaquiddick incident 11 years earlier damaged Ted Kennedy\u2019s chances of being</b> <b>nominated during this year. Despite the \u201cvoodoo economics\u201d attack in this year\u2019s primaries, (*)</b> George H.W. Bush was nominated for Vice President. The failure to resolve the Iran Hostage Crisis helped doom a re-election campaign in, for ten points, what year in which Jimmy Carter lost 44 states to Ronald Reagan?", "answer": "Presidential Election of<b> 1980</b> (prompt on 80)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The previous governor of this state currently serves as head of the Department of Energy, a department that he proposed to eliminate in his 2012 presidential bid. Another former governor of this state promoted the (*) </b> No Child Left Behind Act after he was elected president in 2000. For ten points, name this state that has been governed by Greg Abbott, Rick Perry, and George W. Bush.", "answer": "<b> Texas</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>Hostilities that this treaty failed to end were later resolved through the Treaties of Baden and Rastatt. Under this treaty, 200 years after Tordesillas, Portugal\u2019s control of Brazil was</b> <b>finally recognized. Great Britain gained (+)</b> <b>Gibraltar and the asiento, a monopoly on</b> <b>Gibraltar and the asiento, a monopoly on</b> <b>the slave trade, through this treaty. Under this treaty, a claim to the (*)</b> <b>the slave trade, through this treaty. Under this treaty, a claim to the (*)</b> French throne was renounced by Philip of Anjou so that he could be king of an Iberian country. For ten points, name this treaty that ended the War of Spanish Succession.", "answer": "Treaty (or Peace, etc.) of<b> Utrecht</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This man claimed New England was not guilty of an intent to dissolve the Union in a speech against James Monroe\u2019s conscription plan. Following John Tyler\u2019s decision to break</b> <b>with party lines, this man was the only member of Tyler\u2019s (+)</b> <b>cabinet not to resign. In</b> <b>cabinet not to resign. In</b> <b>a reply to Robert Hayne, this man declared that the US government was \u201cmade (*)</b> <b>a reply to Robert Hayne, this man declared that the US government was \u201cmade (*)</b> for the people, made by the people, and answerable to the people.\u201d For ten points, name this Massachusetts senator who said \u201cLiberty and Union, now and forever, one and inseparable!\u201d", "answer": "Daniel<b> Webster</b> ", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>In this modern day country, Eyre Coote was victorious at the Battle of Wandiwash,</b> <b>leading to the end of France\u2019s presence here during the (+)</b> <b>Carnatic theatre of the</b> <b>Seven Years\u2019 War. A gunpowder-dampening rainstorm helped Robert Clive gain a</b> <b>victory against Mir (*) </b> Jafar in this modern-day country. For ten points, name this country where the Battle of Plassey enabled the dominance of a British joint stock company and, later, the British Raj?", "answer": "<b> India</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}